

+92.343.0012556



m.mazharwattoo@gmail.com



Gulberg 2, Lahore, Pakistan

Summary

I am a full stack .NET developer having over all three years experience in development .I have expertise in following tools and technologies SharePoint, Asp.net mvc, Desktop Application development, Asp.net core, Restful Web API, Web scraping ,SSRS Reporting, JavaScript, and fronted technologies like HTML, CSS ,Bootstrap etc.

I am passoniate to learn new tools and technologies related to Machine learning and Data science.

Skills

ASP.NET MVC | Entity FrameWork | SSRS | .Net Core | Ajax | API writing and Integration | Bootstrap | C# | Desktop Application Development | Git Version Control System | GITHUB | HTML5 | JavaScript | Jquery | LINQ | Machine Learning | Microsoft .NET | MS SQL Server | Object Oriented Design | Pandas | Python | SharePoint | XML

Experience

Jul 2019 - Present

Software Engineer

Ghost Digital & Data (GD&D), Lahore, Pakistan

- Participate in requirements analysis
- Collaborate with internal teams to produce software design and architecture
- Write clean, scalable code using .NET programming languages
- Test and deploy applications and systems
- Revise, update, refactor and debug code
- Improve existing software
- Serve as an expert on applications and provide technical support

Nov 2019 - Dec 2020

Software Engineer

Animal Quarantine Department Lahore, Govt of Pakistan, Lahore, Pakistan

"The Animal Quarantine Department (AQD) is an attached department of Ministry of National Food Security & Research.

AQD provide's quarantine, inspection and certification services at seven different locations across Pakistan".

AQD is my client . I am develping an window based application for managing their Import & Export certificates and intenal document management system.

Jan 2019 - Jun 2019

ASP.NET Developer

Originator IT Solution, Lahore, Pakistan

- Utilize established development tools, guidelines and conventions including but not limited to ASP.NET, SQL Server, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and C#/VB.NET Prepare and maintain code for various .Net applications and resolve any defects in systems.
- Prepare test based applications for various .Net applications.
- Enhance existing systems by analyzing business objectives,
- preparing an action plan and identifying areas for modification and improvement

Manage defect tracking system and resolve all issues and prepare update for systems. Investigate and develop skills in new technologies

 Create technical specifications and test plans Monitor everyday activities of system and provide require support.

Aug 2018 - Feb 2019

Email Marketing

Digital Estimation, Lahore, Pakistan

Here my responsibility were to collect Email Id using Different website and tools and then send Emails of Our Business Services.

Aug 2015 - Mar 2018

Program Coordinator

EVS Professional Training Institute, Lahore, Pakistan

- Manage all daily Tasks
- Coordinates with students
- coordinates with instructors
- Social Media Marketing
- Fee collection and management

Education

2021 PAF IT Academy Lahore

Certification

Data Mining

Incomplete

2021 Presidential Initiative for Artificial Intelligence and Computing

Diploma

Artificial Intelligence, Computer Vision, Robotics/Machine Learning, DATA SCIENCE, Linux, Deep Learning, Git

Incomplete

2020 A Kaggle(Online)

Certification

Python Programming

Incomplete

2020 Kaggle (Online)

Certification

Data Visualization

Incomplete

2020 Kaggle Online

Certification

Incomplete

2020 Kaggle (Online)

Certification

Introduction To Machine Learning

Incomplete

2020 Kaggle (Online) Certification Incomplete 2019 University Of Engineering and Technology Lahore Bachelors in Science, BS Computer Science Database System, Object Oriented Programming, Data Structure, **Programming Fundamental** CGPA: 3.0/4 2018 **EVS Professional Training Institute.** Certification, ASP.NET.MVC C#, ASP.NET MVC Completed 2015 **Govt.College Gulburg Lahore** Intermediate/A-Level, ICS Computer Science, Mathematics Percentage: 74%

Projects

Walkers360-Questionnaire

http://walkers360/QuestionnaireDashboard

Walkers is a leading international law firm. We advise on the laws of Bermuda, the British Virgin Islands, the Cayman Islands, Guernsey, Ireland and Jersey.

Walkers360 is a Enterprise application for Walkersglobal team.

We at GD&D are implementing new feature "Questionnaire" in that application.

- In this feature admin can create a Questionnaire.
- Each Questionnaire consists of diffrents sections and questions
- Each Question consist of specific response type.
- Each question consist of sub questions and pre-request conditions .
- Each question can be mandatory or optional
- After creating question admin can enable and distribute to diffrents entity contacts .
- Distribution can be to "manster Group", "master sub group" "master collaborative", "collborative" or "simple distribution".
- After Distribution Questionnaire cannot be editable but can be of new verion or create a new copy.
- admin can amanage questionnaire and view Distributions on distributions screen
- an automatically and manually email will b send to contacts and internal management team on diffrent Questionnaire related events.
- There is Emails Template management screen where admin can manage email templates.
- after distribution an sync process run that enabe questionnaire to visiable to client and client can submit /save as draft questionnaire.

Animal Quarantine Department Lahore Imports & Exports management System

Animal Quarantine Department Lahore Imports Exports and intenal documents management management System is a window based management system that management all there Imports exports certificates and related finnace and AQD admin can generate reports of previous imports exports and customers etc.

Walkers Global- SharePoint

https://kysp16web01p.walkersglobal.com/

Walkers is a leading international law firm. They provide legal, corporate, compliance and fiduciary services to global

corporations, financial institutions, capital markets participants and investment fund managers. Our clients are the most innovative firms and institutions across the financial markets, and rely on us for our ability to provide solutions to their most important legal and business issues. They develop globally-minded, entrepreneurial lawyers who are experts in their field and committed to client service. Walkers is consistently ranked in the top tier of the leading global legal directories. Recognized for being a 'dynamic team that is very user friendly', a regular comment by clients is that Walkers is the "go-to" firm for offshore legal advice.

We are developing an intranet Sharepoint Solution which is used for internal documents sharing, walkers internal Business processes.

Nuvella Billing System

http://devbilling.vurella.com/

Vurella is Customer Retailer system which provide Integration of products telephone with technology.

Please visit http://www.vurella.com/ for more detail vurela.

OnlineShop.com

A full functional Commerce Web application developed using asp.net mvc 5 and Entity framework 6.0 code first approach.

Originator Accounts API

Builds accounting API using ASP.NET core and Entity framework code first approach

Originator Project Management

Originator Project Management is an desktop application to manage the project activities, Assign Project to the Resource and track the project current situation ,Project Manager can assign tasks to the resources and track their productivity and take daily screening of resources activities.

EmanZara

EmanZara is a Desktop point of sale and Inventory Management system which is full functionally working. It has following majors modules

- Products managements
- Order management
- Automatic Place Order on Corrier serrvices system(MNP&TCS)
- Order Tracking (TCS &MNP Api Integration)
- Accounting
- Reports

Property4You

https://drive.google.com/open?id=1fTEdw5o9XKs6aUiUuK7Hi2_IWrgEp5Z6

This is a student final year project developed in asp.net mvc5 by me.lt is about Property Advertisement and management.

Home Automation

https://drive.google.com/open?id=13Bw5CVKnx4q9c1z13ldcFb1C2FbrcFoU

This is My demo Project in ASP.NET MVC which is basically Related to IOT.

Languages

Punjabi	English	Urdu
Expert	Intermediate	Expert